<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[Personal Notes by ramajd]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Personal Notes by ramajd]]></description>
<link>https://ramajd.github.io/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 22:24:33 +0330</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[New Start]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
after a while finally I decided to restore back my personal weblog, writting
down challenges I'm facing during my daily work. this time I decided to write in
English might be more useful for the ones wthat might face same issues.
</p>

<p>
one of the challenges that I faced with was to choose a proper platform to build
th blog on. using blog services like <i>Blogger</i> or <i>Wordpress</i> they both were
kind of over-qualified for my needs. so I decided to switch to static blog
generators this time.
</p>

<p>
It's been a while that I'm using <a href="https://guix.gnu.org">GNU Guix</a> on my work and it was an opportunity
for me to use <i>GNU Emacs</i> as my common text editor and IDE. working more with
Emacs, I love this editor much more.
</p>


<figure>
<img src="./static/images/emacs_gnu_org_mode.png" alt="emacs_gnu_org_mode.png">

</figure>

<p>
Since for each problem you face, Emacs provides a solution for, it also has a
solution for my Blogging Problem, <i><a href="https://orgmode.org/">Org Mode</a></i>. search for blog tools for Emacs,
there are a bunch of packages already available, and since I was looking for a
simple tool to allow me setup my blog rapidly, I decided to use
<i><a href="https://github.com/bastibe/org-static-blog">org-static-blog</a></i>
</p>

<p>
in order to setup, I just need to add an <a href="https://github.com/bastibe/org-static-blog#examples">initial configuration</a> to my <code>init.el</code>
file, create new post using <code>org-static-blog-create-new-post</code> and run
<code>org-static-blog-publish</code> to generate html files. after that the only thing that
I need to do is to publish generated files to
<a href="https://pages.github.com/">github pages</a>. 
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://ramajd.github.io/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://ramajd.github.io/tag-personal.html">personal</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
  <link>https://ramajd.github.io/2020-12-04-new-start.html</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:10:00 +0330</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
